Contact

marygracesunga@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ marygracesunga (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Healthcare ICU

Certifications

Registered Nurse Registered Nurse Registered Nurse

Neonatal Resuscitation Program Provider

Honors-Awards

Bishop Book Scholarship Recipient Lettie Pate Whitehead Scholarship Recipient

Dean's List 2011-2014
JENESYS 2.0 Selected Participant

Publications

YouTube Channel for my Travel Nursing journey

Mary Grace Sunga

Neonatal Intensive Care Unit Registered Nurse, Former NICU Travel Nurse

Los Angeles, California

Summary

PLEASE, NO TRAVEL NURSE RECRUITER MESSAGES

Neonatal Intensive Care Unit Registered Nurse (BSN) licensed in Virginia (compact), Washington, D.C., California, and Guam. I am currently working in Los Angeles as a full-time NICU Registered Nurse II at a Level IV NICU, the highest acuity level for the NICU. I also work as a Resource NICU RN for a Level III NICU in Los Angeles. I completed 5 contracts as a Travel NICU RN in Los Angeles and the U.S. Territory of Guam. My agencies were Trustaff (Recruiter: Jase Simpson) and Vero RN (Recruiter: Lauren Bencekovich). I created videos in my spare time documenting my travel nurse journey on YouTube, searchable as "marygrace".

I previously worked as permanent staff (RN II) in the NICU with the Inova Health System in Northern Virginia. I completed Nurse Residency as an RN I in Neurosurgery at Virginia Commonwealth University Medical Center, a Level 1 trauma hospital. Prior to becoming an RN, I worked in the Post-Partum unit of a hospital delivering more than 11,000 babies per year. My volunteer experience was in the Newborn Nursery, ICU, and ED. I was also selected to serve a trauma externship in a Level 1 Trauma Hospital.

Experience

Children's Hospital Los Angeles (CHLA) NICU Registered Nurse II April 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

Transitioning from 5 contracts a Travel NICU Registered Nurse for Level III NICU's to advance towards Level IV NICU care. Performing life-sustaining care for newborns that are ill or born premature as early as 23 weeks gestation. Administering medications and vital nutrients, monitoring vital signs/respiratory status, and working within treatment plans individually catered

for each patient and their family. Educating parents with the care of their premature infant post-NICU.

UCLA Health

Resource Registered Nurse for the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit November 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Vero RN

Travel Neonatal ICU Registered Nurse September 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Guam

Working in Neonatal Intensive Care Units as a travel NICU RN of hospitals in need of a temporary RN for 13 week assignments. Continuing to perform life-sustaining care for newborns that are ill or born prematurely as early as 23 weeks gestation.

trustaff

Travel Neonatal ICU Registered Nurse January 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Los Angeles, California

Working in Neonatal Intensive Care Units as a travel NICU RN of hospitals in need of a temporary RN for 13 week assignments. Continuing to perform life-sustaining care for newborns that are ill or born prematurely as early as 23 weeks gestation.

Inova Health System
NICU Registered Nurse II
August 2015 - January 2017 (1 year 6 months)
Neonatal Intensive Care Unit

Performing life-sustaining care for newborns that are ill or born premature as early as 23 weeks gestation. Administering medications and vital nutrients, monitoring vital signs/respiratory status, and working within treatment plans individually catered for each patient and their family. Educating parents with the care of their premature infant post-NICU.

VCU Health System
Registered Nurse
August 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 2 months)
Acute Neuroscience

Managing the care of 4-5 patients recovering from neurosurgeries or facing from neurological diseases or conditions. Administering medications in accordance to the plan of care for each patient. Educating patients on their conditions, maintaining high quality care, and delegating tasks to care partners. Actively taking yearlong residency classes and working towards an Evidence Based Practice presentation under the direction of the UHC/AACN Post-Baccalaureate Nurse Residency Program.

Pediatrix Medical Group
Newborn Hearing Screener
June 2011 - August 2014 (3 years 3 months)

Contracted by Mednax: Pediatrix Medical Group at Inova Fairfax Hospital to conduct state mandated hearing tests on newborns. Educate parents about hearing development, patient data entry using SmartScreener Plus, and document on the Epic EMR system in a timely manner in preparation for patient discharge.

Inova Health System
Trauma Extern
July 2013 - July 2013 (1 month)
Inova Fairfax Hospital

Selected to participate in an observational educational experience with the trauma services team of Inova Fairfax Hospital. Shadowing trauma surgeons during rounds and hospital codes, critical care nurses in the ICU, OR, and ER, respiratory therapists, and radiology technicians. Shadowed the paramedics on ambulatory calls. Present for lectures given by the trauma surgeons, nurses, and trauma research team.

Education

George Mason University
Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2009 - 2014)